<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>_index on Jay Cromwell</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in _index on Jay Cromwell</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Penalty Impact</title>
      <link>/post/penalty_impact/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/penalty_impact/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve always heard &amp;ldquo;the team that commits the least amount of penalties wins the game.&amp;rdquo; It makes sense, but I wanted to dig deeper. Not every penalty is created equal, so which ones truly &amp;ldquo;penalize&amp;rdquo; the team chances of winning? How much impact does having less penalties than the opponent? Let&amp;rsquo;s find out.
First, let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at the Win Probability Added (WPA) from penalties. This measures how much the win probability model from NFLScrapR increases or decreases after the penalty is committed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No Air, No Problem</title>
      <link>/post/passes_at_behind_los/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/passes_at_behind_los/</guid>
      <description>If I were to ask which types of throws Pat Mahomes was the best at in 2018, many would say the deep ball…or the no-look pass…or the left-handed pass…or any other ridiculous pass he made. Not many would think it was the short pass. Actually the shortest pass of all. The Chiefs were by far and away the best team when it came to passes at or behind the line of scrimmage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where Teams are Most Conservative</title>
      <link>/post/third_down_run_percentage/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/third_down_run_percentage/</guid>
      <description>Everyone knows, or should know by now, that passing is more effective than running. This has been proven time and again. What I wanted to know was if teams tended to be more conservative by running the ball more often by field position. More specifically, where are teams running the ball more on third down and why. The below graph show yards to goal line broken down by distance to go over the past 5 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Budapest, Hungary</title>
      <link>/travel/budapest_hungary/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/travel/budapest_hungary/</guid>
      <description>Budapest - February 2019
I could go on and on about Budapest, my favorite city in the world so far, but I&amp;rsquo;ll try to keep it short-ish. We took the train from Vienna and travelling through the countryside, and well, it is pretty much what you&amp;rsquo;d imagine the Hungarian countryside to look like. Lots of nothing and the few towns and cities had a prevalent communism influence with un-maintained, large concrete buildings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prague, Czech Republic</title>
      <link>/travel/prague/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/travel/prague/</guid>
      <description>Prague - February 2019
Prague is one of my all time favorite cities. I most recently went in February. While it was freezing, going to Europe in winter did have a couple of perks, the main being few other tourists. I had been to Prague in the Summer and not having to fight for a spot in front of the Clock Tower was nice to say the least. Another great aspect of Europe in Winter was how beautiful Prague is in the snow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/qb_comparisons/qb_comparisons/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/qb_comparisons/qb_comparisons/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>