<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Jay Cromwell</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Jay Cromwell</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Random Thoughts - What Can Airlines Learn from 2 Chainz</title>
      <link>/post/quick-thoughts-what-can-airlines-learn-from-2-chainz/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/quick-thoughts-what-can-airlines-learn-from-2-chainz/</guid>
      <description>I’ve always joked if I were to open up a restaurant or bar, I wouldn’t focus so much on the menu but on the walls. More specifically, the exterior walls. I’d put up a huge, inviting mural on one of the walls and that would be all the marketing I’d need. I would rely on people seeking out the mural to post pictures in front of the iconic artwork, ultimately promoting my restaurant whether they ate there or not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Future of Airline Travel and Ways Airlines Can Respond</title>
      <link>/post/future-of-airline-travel-and-ways-airlines-can-respond/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/future-of-airline-travel-and-ways-airlines-can-respond/</guid>
      <description>There are many speculations as to when the airline industry will bounce back after the Covid-19 pandemic. It may take years to get back to pre-pandemic levels and perhaps even then there will be aspects of the industry that will never be the same. How airlines and consumers respond to the industry changes will determine the length and severity of recovery. This post outlines how airlines can weather the storm in the upcoming years by pivoting their marketing strategy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Airlines Are Getting Creative During Covid-19</title>
      <link>/post/how-airlines-are-getting-creative-during-covid/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/how-airlines-are-getting-creative-during-covid/</guid>
      <description>By now, you may have heard of the coronavirus that is wreaking havoc of the world’s economy and has lead to over a million deaths worldwide. The seriousness of the COVID-19 pandemic cannot be understated and people must adapt to overcome and eradicate the virus. Similarly, firms and industries are forced to be innovative in order to overcome the impactful storm caused by from COVID-19.
Perhaps no other industry has been impacted by COVID-19 more than the airline industry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predictability, what is it good for?</title>
      <link>/post/play_call_predictions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/play_call_predictions/</guid>
      <description>Football is a game of knowing your opponent and taking advantage of mismatches. This is a big reason why players and coaches study film. Everyone has tendencies and identifying them before they happen in a game is a huge advantage. That is why I wanted to dive into offensive play-calling to highlight play-calling tendencies. Can we accurately predict if a team is going to run or pass purely on the game situation?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s the Hurry?</title>
      <link>/post/whats-the-hurry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/whats-the-hurry/</guid>
      <description>Analytics is taking over football. That much I am sure about. This means we can expect new, innovative ways to coach and manage teams going forward. Panthers owner David Tepper has spoken about being innovative in his approach to filling the head coach role, but also his front office staff. Even ex-GB coach Mike McCarthy has re-branded himself as analytically-minded in hopes of getting a job in 2020. Part of the many, many benefits of analytics taking over football is the ability for teams to optimize play calling and game planning strategies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Penalty Impact</title>
      <link>/post/penalty_impact/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/penalty_impact/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve always heard &amp;ldquo;the team that commits the least amount of penalties wins the game.&amp;rdquo; It makes sense, but I wanted to dig deeper. Not every penalty is created equal, so which ones truly &amp;ldquo;penalize&amp;rdquo; the team chances of winning? How much impact does having less penalties than the opponent? Let&amp;rsquo;s find out.
First, let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at the Win Probability Added (WPA) from penalties. This measures how much the win probability model from NFLScrapR increases or decreases after the penalty is committed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No Air, No Problem</title>
      <link>/post/passes_at_behind_los/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/passes_at_behind_los/</guid>
      <description>If I were to ask which types of throws Pat Mahomes was the best at in 2018, many would say the deep ball…or the no-look pass…or the left-handed pass…or any other ridiculous pass he made. Not many would think it was the short pass. Actually the shortest pass of all. The Chiefs were by far and away the best team when it came to passes at or behind the line of scrimmage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where Teams are Most Conservative</title>
      <link>/post/third_down_run_percentage/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/third_down_run_percentage/</guid>
      <description>Everyone knows, or should know by now, that passing is more effective than running. This has been proven time and again. What I wanted to know was if teams tended to be more conservative by running the ball more often by field position. More specifically, where are teams running the ball more on third down and why. The below graph show yards to goal line broken down by distance to go over the past 5 years.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>