<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Airlines on Jay Cromwell</title>
    <link>/tags/airlines/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Airlines on Jay Cromwell</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/airlines/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro to rtweet: Analyzing Airline&#39;s Social Media Engagement</title>
      <link>/post/intro-to-rtweet-analyzing-airline-s-social-media-engagement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/intro-to-rtweet-analyzing-airline-s-social-media-engagement/</guid>
      <description>I mentioned in another post about the importance of airlines connecting with passengers. A major aspect of that is the method of communication leveraged by the firm. Social media has become the main medium of companies to engage with consumers. With the rise of social media, comes open source data to analyze interactions. Luckily, Twitter has a plethora of data available to its followers.
Twitter Analytics is great for companies to analyze the reach and the effectiveness of their tweets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random Thoughts - What Can Airlines Learn from 2 Chainz</title>
      <link>/post/random-thoughts-what-can-airlines-learn-from-2-chainz/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/random-thoughts-what-can-airlines-learn-from-2-chainz/</guid>
      <description>I’ve always joked if I were to open up a restaurant or bar, I wouldn’t focus so much on the menu but on the walls. More specifically, the exterior walls. I’d put up a huge, inviting mural on one of the walls and that would be all the marketing I’d need. I would rely on people seeking out the mural to post pictures in front of the iconic artwork, ultimately promoting my restaurant whether they ate there or not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Future of Airline Travel and Ways Airlines Can Respond</title>
      <link>/post/future-of-airline-travel-and-ways-airlines-can-respond/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/future-of-airline-travel-and-ways-airlines-can-respond/</guid>
      <description>There are many speculations as to when the airline industry will bounce back after the Covid-19 pandemic. It may take years to get back to pre-pandemic levels and perhaps even then there will be aspects of the industry that will never be the same. How airlines and consumers respond to the industry changes will determine the length and severity of recovery. This post outlines how airlines can weather the storm in the upcoming years by pivoting their marketing strategy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Airlines Are Getting Creative During Covid-19</title>
      <link>/post/how-airlines-are-getting-creative-during-covid/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/how-airlines-are-getting-creative-during-covid/</guid>
      <description>By now, you may have heard of the coronavirus that is wreaking havoc of the world’s economy and has lead to over a million deaths worldwide. The seriousness of the COVID-19 pandemic cannot be understated and people must adapt to overcome and eradicate the virus. Similarly, firms and industries are forced to be innovative in order to overcome the impactful storm caused by from COVID-19.
Perhaps no other industry has been impacted by COVID-19 more than the airline industry.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>